Guide to the Rosa Club Records, 1923 - 1952
Rosa Club Records, 1923 - 1952
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)
1000-174
0.75
1
The Rosa Physics Club was named for an Wesleyan alumnus, Edward B. Rosa, class of 1886. The purpose of the Rosa Club was to promote an interest in physics and its applications, and included student and faculty members.
The collection consists of three volumes of minutes of Rosa Club meetings. In addition to minutes, the volumes also include rosters, election information, budgetary information, and other administrative documents.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Given by Professor Tom Morgan in July 1992.
Historical Note
In 1923, the Rosa Club was founded by the members of the defunct Radio Club. The Rosa Physics Club was named for an Wesleyan alumnus, Edward B. Rosa, class of 1886, a physicist, and physics professor. The purpose of the Rosa Club was to promote an interest in physics and its applications, and this collection documents the club's existence from 1923 until 1952. The club was made up of physics students and a few professors. There were annual officer elections each May for the executive committee positions of faculty representative and student president, vice-president, and secretary-treasurer, who was the student responsible for taking the minutes of each meeting. According to the minutes, there were requirements to be part of the club, mostly in regard to the number or level of classes taken in the physics department, meaning that the members were exclusively physics majors, mostly juniors and seniors, although any physics graduate students and professors were welcome to join the club. The meetings were held twice a month, and each meeting included a report of the previous meeting, new business, a presentation of some scientific news, and a speaker, often a professor or student presenting research.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of three volumes of minutes of Rosa Club meetings. In addition to minutes, the volumes also include rosters, election information, budgetary information, and other administrative documents.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.; Rosa, Edward B. (Edward Bennett), 1861-1921.; Physics--Societies, etc.; Physics--Study and teaching (Higher)--United States.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Loose items
    These items were tucked inside volume 1.
    - Constitution of the Rosa Club of Wesleyan University (Folder 1)
      2 copies from October 15, 1935, and 2 copies undated.
    - Postcard: Scott Laboratory, October 26, 1950 (Folder 1)
      To Professor Caddy from K.S Van Dyke.
    - Postcard: Announcement of a special open meeting on the life of Edward B. Rosa, class of 1886 (Folder 1)
  - 1923-1934 (Volume 1)
    - Page 2, November 19, 1923
      Elected officers: president, F.E. Lord class of 1924; vice president, N. W. Storer, class of 1923; secretary treasurer, Charles Mingins, class of 1925; faculty member of the executive committee, Professor W. G. Cady.
    - Page 5, December 3, 1923
    - Page 6, December 17, 1923
    - Page 7, January 14, 1924
    - Page 8, February 25, 1924
    - Page 9, March 10, 1924
    - Page 10, March 24, 1924
    - Page 11, April 7, 1924
    - Page 12, May 12, 1924
    - Page 13, May 26, 1924
    - Page 15, October 24, 1924
    - Page 16, October 28, 1924
      Elected officers: president, Charles Mingins; vice president, Thorndike; secretary/treasurer, Bradway.
    - Page 17, November 4, 1924
    - Page 18, November 18, 1924
    - Page 19, December 2, 1924
    - Page 20, December 16, 1924
    - Page 21, January 7, 1925
    - Page 22, January 21, 1925
    - Page 23, February 10, 1925
    - Page 24, February 24, 1925
    - Page 25, March 10, 1925
    - Page 26, March 24, 1925
    - Page 27, April 21, 1925
    - Page 28, May 18, 1925
    - Page 30, November 9, 1925
      Elected officer: president, Thorndike.
    - Page 31, November 16, 1925
    - Page 33, December 7, 1925
    - Page 35, January 11, 1926
    - Page 36, February 15, 1926
    - Page 37, March 1, 1926
    - Page 38, March 22, 1926
    - Page 39, April 26, 1926
    - Page 40, May 3, 1926
    - Page 41 May 17, 1926
      Elected officers: president, R. S. Durham; vice president, J. J. Williams; secretary/treasurer, T. H. Briggs.
    - Page 43, October 25, 1926
    - Page 44, November 8, 1926
    - Page 45, November 23, 1926
    - Page 46, December 13, 1926
    - Page 47, January 10, 1927
    - Page 48, February 14, 1927
    - Page 50, March 1, 1927
    - Page 51, March 14, 1927
    - Page 52, March 28, 1927
    - Page 53, April 11, 1927
    - Page 54, April 25, 1927
      Includes roster pasted in.
    - Page 55, May 9, 1927
    - Page 56, May 23, 1927
      Elected officers: president, George Langreth; vice president, Edwin Schneider; secretary/treasurer, Burton Doolittle
    - Page 58, October 18, 1927
    - Page 60, November 2, 1927
    - Page 62, November 15, 1927
    - Page 63, November 29, 1927
    - Page 65, March 5, 1928
    - Page 67, March 12, 1928
    - Page 68, March 26, 1928
    - Page 70, May 7, 1928
    - Page 72, May 28, 1928
      Elected officers: president, Schneider; vice president, Doolittle; secretary/treasurer, Page R. Heldreth
    - Page 74, October 1, 1928
    - Page 75, November 26, 1928
    - Page 76 December 10, 1928
    - Page 77, January 14, 1929
    - Page 79, March 25, 1925
    - Page 80, April 29, 1929
    - Page 81, May 27, 1929
      Elected officers: president, Dwight North; vice president, Lonacre; secretary/treasurer, Paul D. Zotter
    - Page 82, October 7, 1929
    - Page 84, October 21, 1929
    - Page 86, November 25, 1929
    - Page 88, January 13, 1930
    - Page 91, February 25, 1930
    - Page 92, March 10, 1930
    - Page 94, undated
    - Page 96, April 22, 1930
    - Page 98, October 30, 1930
      Elected officers: president, J. R. Hagen; vice president, A. F. Newark; secretary treasurer, W. L. May.
    - Page 99, November 10, 1930
    - Page 102, November 24, 1930
    - Page 106, December 8, 1930
    - Page 110, January 12, 1931
    - Page 111, February 23, 1931
    - Page 115, March 9, 1931
    - Page 117, March 23, 1931
    - Page 119, April 13, 1931
    - Page 121, April 27, 1931
    - Page 122, May 11, 1931
    - Page 122, May 15, 1931
    - Page 122, May 25, 1931
    - Page 124, October 1, 1931
      Elected officers: president, J. M. McNabb; vice president, W. L. May; secretary/treasurer, F. L. Quimby, Jr.
    - Page 125, October 12, 1931
    - Page 126, October 26, 1931
    - Page 128, November 9, 1931
    - Page 128, November 23, 1931
    - Page 129, December 7, 1931
    - Page 130, January 11, 1932
    - Page 131, February 23, 1932
    - Page 131, March 14, 1932
    - Page 132, April 11, 1932
    - Page 132, April 25, 1932
    - Page 137, May 9, 1932
    - Page 138, May 23, 1932
      Includes roster pasted into the volume.
    - Page 139, September 26, 1932
      Elected officers: president, Kent; vice president, Lessmann; secretary/treasurer, R. N. Davis, Jr.
    - Page 139, October 10, 1932
    - Page 141, October 20, 1932
    - Page 142, November 3, 1932
    - Page 143, November 14, 1932
    - Page 145, November 28, 1932
    - Page 146, December 12, 1932
    - Page 147, January 9, 1933
    - Page 148, February 13, 1933
    - Page 149, February 27, 1933
    - Page 150, March 13, 1933
    - Page 151, April 24, 1933
    - Page 152, May 8, 1933
    - Page 153, May 22, 1933
      Elected officers: president, Scott; vice president, Cooney; secretary/treasurer, Müller.
    - Page 155, October 9, 1933
    - Page 156, Amendment proposed
    - Page 157, October 12, 1933
    - Page 159, October 23, 1933
    - Page 161, November 9, 1933
    - Page 165, January 11, 1934
    - Page 167, February 15, 1934
    - Page 169, May 11, 1934
      Elected officers: president, A. H. Taylor; vice president, J. F. Müller; secretary/treasurer, H. K. Burr.
    - Page 170, Dues 1933-1934
    - Page 172, Dues 1932-1933
    - Page 173, Balance sheet 1932-1933
    - Page 175, Dues for 1931-1932
    - Page 176, Roster/Attendance
  - 1934-1940 (Volume 2)
    - Page 2, Members/Roster/Dues/Attendance, 1934-1935
    - Page 4, October 22, 1934
    - Page 6, November 12, 1934
    - Page 8, November 26, 1934
    - Page 12, December 10, 1934
    - Page 16, January 14, 1935
    - Page 18, January 21, 1935
    - Page 20, February 11, 1935
    - Page 22, February 25, 1935
    - Page 24, March 11, 1935
    - Page 27, March 25, 1935
    - Page 30, April 8, 1935
    - Page 32, April 22, 1935
    - Page 34, May 13, 1935
      Elected officers: president, J. F. Müller; vice president, Dick Brown; secretary/treasurer, Duane F. Carlisle.
    - Page 37, May 27, 1935
    - Page 42, Members/Roster/Attendance/Dues, 1935-1936
    - Page 45, September 30, 1935
    - Page 47, October 15, 1935
    - Page 49, October 28, 1935
    - Page 51, November 11, 1935
    - Page 53, November 25, 1935
    - Page 55, December 9, 1935
    - Page 57, January 13, 1936
    - Page 59, February 10, 1936
    - Page 61, February 24, 1936
    - Page 63, March 9, 1936
    - Page 65, April 20, 1936
    - Page 67, May 11, 1936
    - Page 69, May 25, 1936
    - Page 72, 1936-1937 Roster/Attendance/Dues
    - Page 75, October 2, 1936
      Elected officers: president, Thomas; vice president, Brown; secretary/treasurer, B. D. Wright.
    - Page 77, November 17, 1936
    - Page 79, December 15, 1936
    - Page 81, January 12, 1937
    - Page 82, March 2, 1937
    - Page 84, March 16, 1937
    - Page 85, March 22, 1937
    - Page 87, April 6, 1937
    - Page 88, April 20, 1937
    - Page 89, April 24, 1937
    - Page 90, May 4, 1937
    - Page 91, May 18, 1937
    - Page 94, 1937-1938 Roster/Attendance/Dues
    - Page 97, October 6, 1937
    - Page 99, October 25, 1937
    - Page 101, November 8, 1937
    - Page 103, November 22, 1937
    - Page 105, December 13, 1937
    - Page 107, January 7, 1938
    - Page 109, February 14, 1938
    - Page 111, February 28, 1938
    - Page 113, March 14, 1938
    - Page 115, April 11, 1938
    - Page 117, April 25, 1938
    - Page 119, May 9, 1938
    - Page 122, Attendance and Dues 1938-1939
    - Page 124, October 17, 1938
      Elected officers: president, Stilwell; secretary/treasurer, D. E. Wheeler.
    - Page 126, October 24, 1938
    - Page 128, November 14, 1938
    - Page 130, November 28, 1938
    - Page 132, December 12, 1938
    - Page 134, January 9, 1939
    - Page 136, February 13, 1939
    - Page 138, February 27, 1939
    - Page 140, March 13, 1939
    - Page 142, March 27, 1939
    - Page 144, April 10, 1939
    - Page 146, April 24, 1939
    - Page 148, May 8, 1939
    - Page 150, May 22, 1939
    - Page 152, September 25, 1939
    - Page 154, October 9, 1939
    - Page 155, October 24, 1939
    - Page 156, November 13, 1939
    - Page 157, November 27, 1939
    - Page 158, December 11, 1939
    - Page 159, January 15, 1940
    - Page 160, February 19, 1940
    - Page 161, March 25, 1940
    - Page 162, March 11, 1940
    - Page 163, April 8, 1940
    - Page 164, April 29, 1940
    - Page 165, May 3, 1940
    - Page 166, Attendance and Dues, 1939-1940
    - Page 169, Treasurer's Acccount, 1939-1940
    - Page 171, Treasurer's Account, 1938-1939
    - Page 173, Treasury, 1937-1938
    - Page 175, Treasury, 1936-1937
    - Page 177, Treasury, 1935-1936
    - Page 179, Treasury, 1934-1935
  - 1940-1952 (Volume 3)
    - Page 2, Attendance and Dues, 1940-1941
    - Page 4, May 27, 1940
    - Page 6, October 14, 1940
    - Page 8, November 4, 1940
    - Page 10, November 21, 1940
    - Page 11, January 5, 1941
    - Page 12, February 10, 1941
    - Page 13, February 24, 1941
    - Page 14, March 10, 1941
    - Page 15, March 24, 1941
    - Page 16, April 14, 1941
    - Page 17, April 28, 1941
    - Page 18, May 12, 1941
    - Page 21, October 28, 1941
      Elected officers: president, Maynard Waltz; vice president, F. Shore; secretary/treasurer, George W. Morton.
    - Page 23, November 4, 1941
    - Page 25, November 26, 1941
    - Page 27, December 11, 1941
    - Page 29, January 29, 1942
    - Page 33, March 12, 1942
    - Page 36, Treasury Report
    - Page 37, March 30, 1942
    - Page 41, October 20, 1942
      F. Shore elected chairman pro tem.
    - November 24, 1942
      Elected officers: president, F. Shore; vice president, B. Dwight; secretary/treasurer, B. Fitzgerald.
    - Page 45, November 24, 1942
    - Page 49, December 15, 1942
    - Page 56, Members and dues
    - Page 57, November 12, 1946
      Elected officers: president, Dan Little; vice president, John Antonette; secretary/treasurer, M. Van Wyck.
    - Page 59, November 15, 1946
    - Page 60, December 19, 1946
    - Page 61, January 20, 1947
    - Page 63, February 17, 1947
    - Page 64, March 17, 1947
    - Page 65, April 21, 1947
    - Page 66, May 23, 1947
    - Page 68, Members and dues
    - Page 70, November 25, 1947
      Elected officers: president, Bob Vernon; vice president, John Handloser; secretary/treasurer, Charles B. Officer.
    - Page 74, December 12, 1947
    - Page 75, January 13, 1948
    - Page 76, February 5, 1948
    - Page 77, May 18, 1948
      1948-1949 members and dues.
    - Page 78, October 21, 1948
    - Page 79, November 22, 1948
      Elected officer: president, Dick Preston.
    - Page 80, January 10, 1949
    - Page 81, March 14, 1949
      Budget information.
    - Page 82, May 17, 1949
    - Page 83, May 28, 1949
      Elected officers: president, Bob Stearns; vice president, Gary Gordon; secretary/treasurer, Howard Johnson.
    - Page 84, State of the Treasury
    - Page 85, 1949-1950 roster and dues
    - Page 86, November 1949
    - Page 89, January 6, 1950
    - Page 92, January 18, 1950
    - Page 93, February 15, 1950
    - Page 94, March 1, 1950
    - Page 95, April 19, 1950
    - Page 96, State of the Treasury
    - Page 97, 1950-1951 members
    - Page 98, November 1, 1950
      Elected officers: president, John Olson; vice president, Bob Willett; secretary/treasurer, George S. Stanford.
    - Page 99, November 16, 1950
    - Page 101, December 18, 1950
    - Page 103, May 24, 1951
    - Page 105, June 3, 1951
      Elected officers: president, John C. Smith; vice president, Charles Deeley; secretary/treasurer, Robert Kelman.
    - Page 106, State of the Treasury 1950-1951
    - Page 107, October 8, 1951
    - Page 108, October 11, 1951
    - Page 110, November 8, 1951
    - Page 112, December 17, 1951
    - Page 113, February 15, 1952
    - Page 114, Treasurer's Report as of February 26, 1952
    - Page 115, March 20, 1952
    - Page 117, April 10, 1952
    - Page 119, May 3, 1952
    - Page 248, Treasurer's Acct. 1951-1952
    - Page 249, Members
    - Page 250, Treasurer's Account, 1946-1947
    - Page 251, Treasurer's Account, 1939-1940